<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="ratype_activities">

	<title>Activities</title>

	<para>The single activity object for &THIS.RA; Resource Adaptor is the <literal>org.mobicents.slee.ra. httpclient.nio.ratype. HttpClientNIORequestActivity</literal> interface. Each activity is mapped to a single HTTP request, and through its interface a SBB may cancel the request, or check the request status. The asynchronous event related to the server response is fired in the activity.</para>
	
	<para>An activity starts when a SBB, executes a request, through the RA SBB Interface, and it ends when the response event is unreferenced.</para>
	
	<para>The <literal>HttpClientNIORequestActivity</literal> interface is defined as follows:</para>
	
	<programlisting language="Java" role="JAVA">
		<![CDATA[
package org.mobicents.slee.ra.httpclient.nio.ratype;

public interface HttpClientNIORequestActivity {

	boolean cancel(boolean mayInterruptIfRunning);

	boolean isCancelled();

	boolean isDone();

}]]>
     </programlisting>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>
				The <literal>cancel(boolean)</literal> method:
			</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Attempts to cancel execution of the request. This attempt will fail if the request has already completed, has already been cancelled, or could not be cancelled for some other reason. If successful, and this request has not started when cancel is called, this request should never run. If the request has already started, then the parameter determines whether the execution of this request should be interrupted in an attempt to stop the request.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>

		<varlistentry>
			<term>
				The <literal>isCancelled()</literal> method:
			</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Returns true if this request was cancelled before it completed normally.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		
		<varlistentry>
			<term>
				The	<literal>isDone()</literal> method:
			</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>Returns true if this request completed. Completion may be due to normal termination, an exception, or cancellation -- in all of these cases, this method will return true.</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>	
</section>